In the previous lesson,
在上次课程中
you saw how the bar plot and point plot functions can be used to
我们学习了如何使用 barplot 和 pointplot 函数绘制条形图
plot a bar chart with a second variables mean on the vertical axis.
主要是将第二个变量的平均值画到纵轴上
Let's extend this bivariate plot of fuel efficiency against
让我们加入变速器类型
the vehicle class into a multivariate plot by adding transmission type.
将有关燃油效率和车辆类型的双变量图表扩展成多变量图表
To do this, all we need to do is add hue equals trans_type to the point plot function.
我们只需要在 pointplot 函数中添加 hue = ‘trans_type’ 参数
Since the dots and bars are overlapping,
因为点和长条之间相互重叠
we should add dodge equals true to offset the two levels slightly.
我们需要添加 dodge = True 参数 使两种类别互相偏移一点
Alternatively, we can change the point plot function into a bar plot function,
我们还可以将 pointplot 改为 barplot
to get an adapted clustered bar chart.
得到一个分组条形图
Even further, we can take one more step back on
我们甚至还可以再进一步
the summarization levels and use the box plot function to get a clustered box plot.
使用箱线图 从而得到一个分组箱线图
We can also adapt heat maps,
热图也可以做出调整
so that instead of color being based on count,
让颜色编码 基于第三变量的平均值
color is based on the mean of a third variable.
而不是计数
Let's change this heat map of fuel efficiency against engine size,
让我们来修改这幅有关燃油效率和发动机排量大小的热图
so that average CO2 output is plotted instead.
使二氧化碳排放量的均值也能在图上展示
There is a weights parameter hist2d that sets
hist2d 函数有一个 weights 参数
how much each data point is worth in the aggregation.
设置每个数据在聚合时的权重
By default, each point's weight is worth one,
默认的权重为 1
so that the colors reflect the total counts.
所以颜色代表了数据点的数量
If we change it so that each point's weight is equal to
如果我们将这里的 weights 改成二氧化碳排放量
its CO2 emissions divided by the number of cars in its bin,
除以每个分组的汽车数量
then the total within each bin will be the average CO2 emissions.
这样每一个分组的总和就是二氧化碳排放量的均值
Our first step is to figure out in which bin each point falls.
我们的第 1 步是对数据进行分组
We compute this using the pandas cut function.
使用 Pandas 里的 cut 函数
In addition to the arguments you've seen before,
除了之前看到过的参数
the labels equals false argument is added so that the bins are identified numerically,
我们将 labels 参数改为 False 使每个分组的索引为数值索引
and we apply as type to make the indexing later easier.
用 astype 使数据类型变成整数型 使后续的索引变得更简单
Next, we count up the number of points that fall in each bin.
之后我们统计每个分组里的数据量
This is done using the groupby and size functions.
这可以通过使用 groupby 和 size 函数得到
This MultiIndex series is kind of hard to work with,
多重索引的 Series 类型不是很方便使用
so we'll use reset index and pivot to put the counts in array form.
所以我们再用 reset_index 和 pivot 方法将计数变成数组的形式
Finally, we use the values attribute to get the number of points as an array.
最后 我们使用 values 属性将数据计数变成一个数组
Now, we can get our point weights using all of these values.
现在 我们得到了计算权重需要的所有数据
We take the CO2 series and divide each element by the number of points in each bin,
我们用 co2 Series 除以每个分组的数据量
using the cut bins vectors for indexing into the right places.
利用 cut 分组的索引确保向量除法中的每个元素都相互对应
We add the weights to the weights parameter,
然后我们将其加入 weights 参数
and then a label to the color bar,
并为颜色条添加了标签
and we've got a heat map plot that looks in line with
最终得到了和我们之间课上画过的散点图
the colored scatter plot that we made earlier in the lesson.
一致的热图